Guide to the Robert K. Merton Papers,
Rare Book and Manuscript Library Columbia University Libraries
- Series IV: Professional Career, 1933-2003
  - Subseries IV.2: Affiliations, 1943-2001
    - Harcourt Brace Jovanovich
      - Correspondence
        - E--General, 1966-1976 (Box 164, Folder 4)
        - F--General, 1972-1976 (Box 164, Folder 5)
        - Fischer, Claude, 1972-1983, (2 Folders) (Box 164, Folder 6-7)
        - G--General, 1954-1984 (Box 164, Folder 8)
        - Giddens, Anthony, 1981 (Box 164, Folder 9)
        - Greissman, Judith, 1970-1981, (2 Folders) (Box 164, Folder 10-11)
        - Greissman, Judith, 1970-1981 (Box 165, Folder 1)
        - H--General, 1968-1978 (Box 165, Folder 2)
        - Homans, George, 1946-1975 (Box 165, Folder 3)
        - Hopkins, Terence and Wallerstein, Immanuel, 1973 (Box 165, Folder 4)
        - Johnson, Allan, 1981-1988, (5 Folders) (Box 165, Folder 5-9)
        - Johnson, Harry, 1966-1972 (Box 165, Folder 10)
        - Jovanovich, William, 1963-1984 (Box 165, Folder 11)
        - K--General, 1964-1983 (Box 165, Folder 12)
        - L--General, 1969-1971 (Box 166, Folder 1)
        - M--General, 1947-1972 (Box 166, Folder 2)
        - Martin, William, 1972 (Box 166, Folder 3)
        - Nisbet, Robert, 1958-1978 (Box 166, Folder 4)
        - O--General, 1971-1978 (Box 166, Folder 5)
        - Official, 1946-1962 (Box 166, Folder 6)
        - P-Q--General, 1964-1976 (Box 166, Folder 7)
        - R--General, 1953-1976 (Box 166, Folder 8)
        - Reid, James, 1963-1964 (Box 166, Folder 9)
        - Roman, Paul, 1971-1978 (Box 166, Folder 10)
        - S--General, 1957-1977, (2 Folders) (Box 166, Folder 11-12)
        - Stark, Rod, 1971-1978, (2 Folders) (Box 166, Folder 13-14)
        - Sudnow, David, 1978-1981 (Box 166, Folder 15)
        - Sykes, Gresham, 1973-1978, (2 Folders) (Box 166, Folder 16-17)
        - T--General, 1969-1978 (Box 167, Folder 1)
        - W--General, 1951-1983 (Box 167, Folder 2)
        - Wilson, Logan and Kolb, William, 1946-1952, (2 Folders) (Box 167, Folder 3-4)
        - X-Z--General, 1966 (Box 167, Folder 5)
      - Coser, Lewis and Steffan, Patsy Manuscript, 1986 (Box 167, Folder 6)
      - Honorary Degree Nomination for William Jovanovich, 1984-1987 (Box 167, Folder 7)
      - Paperback Series, 1963-1971 (Box 167, Folder 8)
      - Sociology Series, 1946-1955 (Box 167, Folder 9)
    - Harlem Youth Opportunities Unlimited, Inc.--Consultant, 1962 (Box 167, Folder 10)
    - Harvard University
      - Ad Hoc Committee, 1955-1963 (Box 167, Folder 11)
      - Sociology Advisory Committee, 1981-1984, (2 Folders) (Box 167, Folder 12-13)
    - Institute for Advanced Study--Ad Hoc Committee, 1972-1975 (Box 167, Folder 14)
    - Institute for Development of Educational Activities--Advisory Board, 1977-1981 (Box 167, Folder 15)
    - Institute for Development of Educational Activities--Advisory Board, 1977-1981 (Box 168, Folder 1)
    - Institute for Religious and Social Studies, 1946-1951, (2 Folders) (Box 168, Folder 2-3)
    - Institute for Scientific Information
      - General, 1974-1995, (8 Folders) (Box 168, Folder 4-11)
      - General, 1974-1995, (5 Folders) (Box 169, Folder 1-5)
      - Arts and Humanities Citation Index--Editorial Policy Board, 1978-1982 (Box 169, Folder 6)
      - Conference on Advances in Information Access, 1982-1983 (Box 169, Folder 7)
      - Eugene Garfield Agendas, 1981-1984 (Box 169, Folder 8)
      - Social Sciences Citation Index--Editorial Advisory Board, 1972-1973 (Box 169, Folder 9)
    - Institute of Social and Economic Research--Editorial Advisory Board, 1956 (Box 169, Folder 10)
    - International Council of Nurses, 1969 (Box 169, Folder 11)
    - International Encyclopedia of the Social Sciences--Editorial Council, 1960-1962 (Box 169, Folder 12)
    - International Sociological Association
      - General, 1965-1974 (Box 169, Folder 13)
      - Research Committee on the Sociology of Science, 1966-1973, (4 Folders) (Box 170, Folder 1-4)
    - James Marshall Fund--Board of Directors, 1961-1966 (Box 170, Folder 5)
    - John Simon Guggenheim Memorial Foundation
      - Fellowship Nominations, 1962-1984 (Box 170, Folder 6)
      - President Search Committee, 1984 (Box 170, Folder 7)
      - Western Hemisphere Competition--Referee Reports, 1969-1983 (Box 170, Folder 8)
    - Journal of Applied Behavioral Sciences--Editorial Board, 1965 (Box 170, Folder 9)
    - Mary Conover Mellon Foundation for the Advancement of Education--Advisory Committee, 1946-1952 (Box 170, Folder 10)
    - Massachusetts Institute of Technology--School of Humanities and Social Sciences--Review Committee, 1956-1957, 1988, (2 Folders) (Box 170, Folder 11-12)
    - Moton Center for Independent Studies, 1974 (Box 171, Folder 1)
    - National Academy of Sciences
      - General, 1976-1978 (Box 171, Folder 2)
      - Ballots, 1969-1977, (4 Folders) (Box 171, Folder 3-6)
      - Chairman Reports, 1976-1978 (Box 171, Folder 7)
      - Nominations, 1976 (Box 171, Folder 8)
      - Temporary Nominating Group, 1972-1979 (Box 171, Folder 9)
    - National Commission for the Study of Nursing and Nursing Education, 1967-1972 (Box 171, Folder 10)
    - National Research Council--Joint Committee, 1949-1950 (Box 171, Folder 11)
    - National Science Foundation
      - Correspondence, 1986 (Box 171, Folder 12)
      - Grant--Theoretical Sociology: Unintended Consequences to the Self-fulfilling Prophecy, 1980-1984, (3 Folders) (Box 171, Folder 13-15)
      - Oversight Panel, 1986 (Box 172, Folder 1)
      - Proposal Evaluation, 1985 (Box 351, Folder 10)
      - 172 (Box 172, Folder 10)
      - Referee Reports, 1947-1977, (2 Folders) (Box 172, Folder 2-3)
    - National Taiwan University--Department and Graduate Institute of Sociology, 1986-1987 (Box 172, Folder 4)
    - New York Society of Fellows, 1986-1987 (Box 172, Folder 5)
    - Philosophy of Science Governing Board, 1948-1954 (Box 172, Folder 6)
    - Princeton University--Institute for Advanced Study--Ad Hoc Committee, 1969 (Box 172, Folder 7)
    - Reynal and Hitchcock, Inc., 1945-1946 (Box 172, Folder 8)
    - Rockefeller Foundation, 1943-1956, (2 Folders) (Box 172, Folder 9-10)
    - Rockefeller University, 1979-1988 (Box 172, Folder 11)
    - Rural Sociology Committee of Argentina--Corresponding Member, 1959 (Box 237, Folder 2)
    - Russell Sage Foundation
      - General, 1967-1998, (2 Folders) (Box 172, Folder 12-13)
      - Administrative, 1972-2001 (Box 173, Folder 1)
      - Conferences and Seminars
        - General, 1988 (Box 173, Folder 2)
        - Pragmatic Side of Social Science, 1983 (Box 173, Folder 3)
      - Correspondence
        - General, 1986-2000 (Box 173, Folder 4)
        - Wanner, Eric, 1984-1998, (4 Folders) (Box 173, Folder 5-8)
        - Wildavsky, Aaron, 1977 (Box 173, Folder 9)
      - Farewell Event, 1999 (Box 173, Folder 10)
      - Institutional Diary, 1973-1977 (Box 173, Folder 11)
      - Programs, 1977-1978 (Box 173, Folder 12)
      - Reports, 1977 (Box 174, Folder 1)
      - Staff, 1975-1977 (Box 174, Folder 2)
      - Visiting Scholar Program, 1991 (Box 174, Folder 3)
    - Salk Institute
      - Council for Biology in Human Affairs, 1969-1973 (Box 174, Folder 4)
      - East, 1969 (Box 174, Folder 5)
    - Science News Weekly--Advisory Board, 1980-1984 (Box 174, Folder 6)
    - Sloan Foundation--Book Committee, 1976-1996 (Box 174, Folder 7)
    - Social Science Research Council
      - General, 1946-1970, (3 Folders) (Box 174, Folder 8-10)
      - Committee on the History and Sociology of Science, 1955-1956 (Box 174, Folder 11)
      - Science Indicators Subcommittee, 1975 (Box 174, Folder 12)
    - Society--Board of Editors, 1994 (Box 174, Folder 13)
    - Society for Social Studies of Science (4S)
      - General, 1976-1987, (2 Folders) (Box 174, Folder 14-15)
      - Correspondence, 1975-1979, (2 Folders) (Box 175, Folder 1-2)
      - First Annual Meeting, 1975-1976 (Box 175, Folder 3)
      - First Presidential Address, undated (Box 175, Folder 4)
      - Founding, 1975-1976 (Box 175, Folder 5)
      - John Desmond Bernal Award, 1982-1986 (Box 175, Folder 6)
      - Meetings, 1976-1977 (Box 175, Folder 7)
      - Newsletters, 1975-1985 (Box 175, Folder 8)
    - Sociological Abstracts--Advisory Board, 1956-1976 (Box 176, Folder 1)
    - Sydenham Hospital--Institute of Community Relations, 1947-1948 (Box 176, Folder 2)
    - Tel Aviv University--Institute for the History and Philosophy of Science and Ideas, 1982-1988, (2 Folders) (Box 176, Folder 3-4)
    - Temple University
      - General, 1961-1989 (Box 176, Folder 5)
      - Alumni Fellow, 1980-1981, (2 Folders) (Box 176, Folder 6-7)
    - Time-Life Books, 1966 (Box 176, Folder 8)
    - Trans-Action--Board of Advisory Editors, 1963-1966 (Box 176, Folder 9)
    - Tulane University--Advisory Committee of the Urban Life Research Institute, 1956 (Box 176, Folder 10)
    - United States Commission on Civil Rights, 1974, undated (Box 176, Folder 11)
    - University of Chicago School of Law--Research Advisory Board on the Behavioral Sciences, 1952-1961 (Box 176, Folder 12)
    - University of Pennsylvania--Advisory Committee on the Urban Strategies Project, 1969-1970 (Box 176, Folder 13)
    - University of Puerto Rico--Consultant, 1961-1966 (Box 176, Folder 14)
    - The Van Leer Jerusalem Foundation, 1970-1971 (Box 177, Folder 1)
    - World Academy of Art and Science, 1962-1963 (Box 177, Folder 2)
    - World Book Encyclopedia--Consulting Editor on Sociology, 1964-1967, (2 Folders) (Box 177, Folder 3-4)
    - World Society for Ekistics, 1973-1978 (Box 177, Folder 5)
    - American Sociological Association--Talcott Parsons Memorial Session, 1979 (Box 368, Folder 11)
    - Center for Advanced Study in the Behavioral Sciences
      - Beginnings, 1952, 1973-1990 (Box 368, Folder 12)
      - Program on Science, Technology, and Society (POSTS), 1971-1988 (Box 368, Folder 13)
    - Disaster Research Group, 1960-1969 (Box 369, Folder 1)
    - Eastern Sociological Society--Statement of Presidential Theme, 1970-1995 (Box 369, Folder 2)
    - Ford Foundation, 1951 (Box 369, Folder 3)
    - National Academy of Sciences--Notice of Membership Election, 1958-1968 (Box 369, Folder 4)
    - Russell Sage Foundation
      - 80th Birthday Party, 1990 (Box 369, Folder 5)
      - Memoranda, 1985 (Box 369, Folder 6)
      - Trustees Talk, undated (Box 369, Folder 7)
    - Science Citation Index--Early History, 1959-1989 (Box 369, Folder 8)
    - Society for Social Studies of Science (4S)--First Banquet Meeting, 1976 (Box 369, Folder 9)
    - American Sociological Society
      - Membership Totals, 1995 (Box 443, Folder 4)
      - Presidency, 1944-1961 (Box 443, Folder 5)
    - National Academy of Sciences--Boudon, Raymond, 1991 (Box 443, Folder 6)
    - Russell Sage Foundation
      - 80th Birthday Party, 1990 (Box 443, Folder 7)
      - Book Party for Marty Lipset, 1995 (Box 443, Folder 8)
      - Reception for Merton, 1994 (Box 443, Folder 9)
  - Subseries IV.3: Awards and Honors, 1959-2001
    Awards and Honors encompass merits presented to Merton by the professional community at large, including chairmanships, honorary degrees, prizes, and most notably, the National Medal of Science. This subseries is comprised of acceptance speeches, ceremonial programs, invitations, press clippings, and correspondence. A complete list of awards can be found in Merton's curriculum vitae in Series I. Award information relating to specific organizations is also filed in Subseries IV.2
    - Academia Europaea--Foreign Member, 1992 (Box 177, Folder 6)
    - American Academy of Arts and Sciences--Talcott Parsons Prize for Social Science, 1979-1980 (Box 177, Folder 7)
    - American Council of Learned Societies--Prize for Distinguished Scholarship in the Humanities, 1959-1962 (Box 177, Folder 8)
    - American Society of Criminology--Edwin L. Sutherland Award, 1996 (Box 177, Folder 9)
    - American Sociological Association
      - Common Wealth Award of Distinguished Service, 1979-1980 (Box 177, Folder 10)
      - Cooley-Mead Award in Social Psychology, 1997 (Box 177, Folder 11)
      - R.K. Merton Prize for Research in the Sociology of Science and Technology, 1983-1984 (Box 177, Folder 12)
    - Derek De Solla Price Medal in Scientometrics, 1995 (Box 177, Folder 13)
    - Derek De Solla Price Medal in Scientometrics, 1995 (Box 351, Folder 11)
    - Honorary Degrees
      - General, 1968-1996 (Box 178, Folder 1)
      - Brandeis University, 1982-1983 (Box 178, Folder 2)
      - Cleveland State University, 1977 (Box 178, Folder 3)
      - Colgate University, 1966-1967 (Box 178, Folder 4)
      - Emory University, 1965 (Box 178, Folder 5)
      - Harvard University, 1980-1984 (Box 178, Folder 6)
      - The Hebrew University of Jerusalem, 1980 (Box 178, Folder 7)
      - Jagiellonian University, 1988-1989, (3 Folders) (Box 178, Folder 8-10)
      - John Jay College of Criminal Justice (declined), 1988 (Box 178, Folder 11)
      - Kalamazoo College, 1970-1974 (Box 178, Folder 12)
      - Long Island University, 1995-1996 (Box 178, Folder 13)
      - Loyola University, Chicago, 1969-1970 (Box 178, Folder 14)
      - New School for Social Research, 1994-1995 (Box 178, Folder 15)
      - Oxford University, 1985-1987 (Box 178, Folder 16)
      - State University of New York, Board of Regents, 1983-1985 (Box 178, Folder 17)
      - State University of New York at Albany, 1984-1986 (Box 179, Folder 1)
      - Temple University, 1956-1963 (Box 179, Folder 2)
      - Tulane University, 1971 (Box 179, Folder 3)
      - Universita di Bologna, 1995-1996 (Box 179, Folder 4)
      - University of Athens, 1999 (Box 179, Folder 5)
      - University of Chicago, 1968-1971 (Box 179, Folder 6)
      - University of Madrid, 1995-1998 (Box 179, Folder 7)
      - University of Maryland, 1982 (Box 179, Folder 8)
      - University of Oslo, 1991-1994 (Box 179, Folder 9)
      - University of Pennsylvania, 1979-1980 (Box 179, Folder 10)
      - Western Reserve University, 1966 (Box 179, Folder 11)
      - Yale University, 1968-1969 (Box 179, Folder 12)
    - John Simon Guggenheim Memorial Foundation Fellowship
      - General, 1961-1983, (2 Folders) (Box 179, Folder 13-14)
      - Application Material, 1962 (Box 179, Folder 15)
    - MacArthur Foundation--Prize Fellows Award
      - General, 1980-1996 (Box 179, Folder 16)
      - General, 1980-1996 (Box 180, Folder 1)
      - Correspondence
        - General, 1980-1985 (Box 180, Folder 2)
        - Congratulatory, 1983-1984, (2 Folders) (Box 180, Folder 3-4)
      - Fellows Reunion, 1986 (Box 180, Folder 5)
    - Memorial Sloan-Kettering Cancer Center--Award for Outstanding Support of Biomedical Science, 1981 (Box 180, Folder 6)
    - National Medal of Science, 1991-1994 (Box 180, Folder 7)
    - National Medal of Science, 1994, (2 Folders) (Box 351, Folder 12-13)
    - New York Academy of Sciences--Honorary Life Member, 1997 (Box 180, Folder 8)
    - Pacific Lutheran University--Robert K. Merton Prize in Sociology, 1993-1995 (Box 180, Folder 9)
    - Qualitative Research Consultants Association Award, 1991 (Box 180, Folder 10)
    - Royal Swedish Academy of Sciences--Foreign Member, 1975-1976 (Box 180, Folder 11)
    - Temple University--Phi Beta Kappa, 1977 (Box 180, Folder 12)
    - Who's Who in America--First Achievement Award in the Social Sciences and Social Policy, 1975-1985, (2 Folders) (Box 180, Folder 13-14)
    - Who's Who in America--First Achievement Award in the Social Sciences and Social Policy, 1984 (Box 351, Folder 14)
    - General--Compilation, 1980-1997 (Box 369, Folder 10)
    - American Nurses' Association Award, 1972 (Box 369, Folder 11)
    - Derek De Solla Price Medal in Scientometrics, 1995 (Box 369, Folder 12)
    - Eastern Sociological Society--Award, 1978 (Box 369, Folder 13)
    - Honorary Degrees
      - Brandeis University, 1982 (Box 369, Folder 14)
      - Columbia University, 1984-1985 (Box 369, Folder 15)
      - Harvard University, 1980 (Box 369, Folder 16)
      - The Hebrew University of Jerusalem, 1980 (Box 369, Folder 17)
      - Jagiellonian University, 1989 (Box 369, Folder 18)
      - Long Island University, 1995-1996 (Box 369, Folder 19)
      - State University of New York at Albany, 1986 (Box 369, Folder 20)
      - State University of New York, Board of Regents, 1983-1984 (Box 369, Folder 21)
      - Universita di Bologna, 1995-1996 (Box 369, Folder 22)
      - University of Athens, 1999 (Box 369, Folder 23)
      - University of Leiden, 1965 (Box 370, Folder 1)
      - University of Madrid, 1995-1999 (Box 370, Folder 2)
      - University of Maryland, 1982 (Box 370, Folder 3)
      - University of Oslo, 1991-1993 (Box 370, Folder 4)
      - University of Rome, 2001 (Box 370, Folder 5)
      - University of Wales, 1968-1969 (Box 370, Folder 6)
    - Institute for Scientific Information (ISI)--Cathedral of Man Murals, 1981 (Box 370, Folder 7)
    - John Desmond Bernal Award for Outstanding Scholarly Contributions, 1982 (Box 370, Folder 8)
    - National Medal of Science, 1994 (Box 370, Folder 9)
    - New York Academy of Sciences--Honorary Life Member, 1997 (Box 370, Folder 10)
    - Polish Academy of Sciences--Foreign Member, 1997 (Box 370, Folder 11)
    - World Association of Public Opinion Research--Helen Dinerman Award, 2000 (Box 370, Folder 12)
    - Honorary Degrees--Universita di Bologna, 1995-1996 (Box 443, Folder 10)
    - National Medal of Science
      - General, 1994 (Box 443, Folder 11)
      - Correspondence, 1994-1995, (3 Folders) (Box 443, Folder 12 to 14)
      - Local Receptions, 1994 (Box 444, Folder 1)
      - Presentation Program, 1994 (Box 444, Folder 2)
      - Press Coverage, 1994 (Box 444, Folder 3)
  - Subseries IV.4: Columbia University, 1940-2001
    This subseries portrays Merton's faculty affiliation with Columbia University through records related to public lectures, conference and event attendance, departmental involvement, awards, and service on numerous committees. Prominent in this subseries is material detailing Merton's extensive involvement with the Paul F. Lazarsfeld Center for the Social Sciences, a direct descendent of the Bureau of Applied Social Research and the Center for Social Sciences. Merton grouped all material related to Lazarsfeld in this section. Items include original correspondence with Lazarsfeld, material pertaining to Lazarsfeld's life and work, and records related to the creation of the book Qualitative and Quantitative Research: Papers in Honor of Paul F. Lazarsfeld, of which Merton was a contributing editor. The Paul F. Lazarsfeld items in boxes #444-448 were compiled by Merton and contain general musings, notes, and recollections about Lazarsfeld using a variety of themes. It appears that Merton compiled this material in preparation for a talk at the Paul F. Lazarsfeld Colloquium at the Sorbonne in 1994. Also present in this subseries are Merton's Sociology Department administrative files. These files characterize the operations of the department, particularly during the 1970s and 1980s, and Merton's involvement and thoughts regarding departmental procedures and decisions. Topics include faculty, courses, committees, fellowships, and visiting professors.
    - General, 1950-1982 (Box 351, Folder 15)
    - General, 1968-1983, (2 Folders) (Box 180, Folder 15-16)
    - 250th Anniversary Steering Committee, 1996-2000 (Box 180, Folder 17)
    - Ad Hoc Committees
      - General, 1956-1973, (2 Folders) (Box 181, Folder 1-2)
      - Wood, Michael, 1970-1971 (Box 181, Folder 3)
    - Advisory Committee on Communication, 1971-1974 (Box 181, Folder 4)
    - Advisory Committee for Ethnic Studies, 1973 (Box 181, Folder 5)
    - Albert Schweitzer Chair Nominee Committee, 1973-1978 (Box 181, Folder 6)
    - Bicentennial Committee, 1974 (Box 181, Folder 7)
    - Bicentennial Conference, 1952-1955 (Box 351, Folder 16)
    - Bureau of Applied Social Research, 1957-1975 (Box 181, Folder 8)
    - Center for the Social Sciences
      - General, 1973-1975 (Box 181, Folder 9)
      - Ad Hoc Committee, 1975-1976 (Box 181, Folder 10)
      - Advisory Board, 1981 (Box 181, Folder 11)
      - Communications Project, 1980-1981 (Box 181, Folder 12)
      - Correspondence
        - General, 1976-1984, (4 Folders) (Box 181, Folder 13-16)
        - General, 1976-1984 (Box 182, Folder 1)
        - Newsletter, 1979-1981 (Box 182, Folder 2)
        - White, Harrison, 1988-1989 (Box 182, Folder 3)
      - Development, 1976-1985, (2 Folders) (Box 182, Folder 4-5)
      - Stanton, Frank and Wise, George Material, 1976-1981 (Box 182, Folder 6)
    - Clinical Scholars Program, 1974-1975 (Box 182, Folder 7)
    - College of Physicians and Surgeons
      - Committee on Ethics and Values in the Health Sciences, 1971-1972 (Box 182, Folder 8)
      - Dean's Distinguished Lecture Series, 1985-1986 (Box 182, Folder 9)
      - Search Committee Invite, 1970 (Box 182, Folder 10)
    - Columbia College--Science Committee, 1967-1968 (Box 182, Folder 11)
    - Columbia University Press
      - Concise Columbia Encyclopedia and Contemporary Columbia Encyclopedia Consultant, 1988-1989 (Box 182, Folder 12)
      - Correspondence, 1948-1990 (Box 182, Folder 13)
    - Commencement, 1968-1981 (Box 182, Folder 14)
    - Conferences on the Humanities and Public Policy Issues, 1973 (Box 182, Folder 15)
    - Conference on Science and Labor, 1982 (Box 182, Folder 16)
    - Delivery of Special Tabulation Request, 1998 (Floppy Disc) (Box 345)
    - Development, 1981-1983 (Box 182, Folder 17)
    - Doctoral Program Subcommittee on Business Steering Committee, 1971-1972 (Box 182, Folder 18)
    - Emeritus Professors in Columbia (EPIC), 2000 (Box 182, Folder 19)
    - Faculty Affairs Committee, 1970 (Box 182, Folder 20)
    - Faculty Prize Ad Hoc Committee, 1969 (Box 182, Folder 21)
    - Faculty Search Committee, 1968-1969 (Box 182, Folder 22)
    - Faculty Seminar, 1973 (Box 183, Folder 1)
    - Freedom Forum Media Studies Center, 1993 (Box 183, Folder 2)
    - Gannet Center for Media Studies, 1985-1989 (Box 183, Folder 3)
    - General Education Seminars, 1975-1976 (Box 183, Folder 4)
    - Graduate School of Arts and Sciences--Centennial Conference, 1979-1980 (Box 183, Folder 5)
    - History of Physics Laboratory Collaboration--Advisory Committee, 1974-1981 (Box 183, Folder 6)
    - History of Science Club, 1967-1979 (Box 183, Folder 7)
    - History of Science Committee, 1960-1967 (Box 183, Folder 8)
    - Honorary Degree Procedures, 1968-1985 (Box 183, Folder 9)
    - Institute for Social and Economic Research and Policy
      - General, 1998-2001 (Box 183, Folder 10)
      - Paul Lazarsfeld Centennial Event, 2001, (3 Folders) (Box 183, Folder 11-13)
    - Institute for the Study of Science in Human Affairs
      - General, 1964-1971, (2 Folders) (Box 183, Folder 14-15)
      - Proposal, 1962-1965 (Box 184, Folder 1)
    - Italian Academy for Advanced Studies in America
      - General, 1991-1995 (Box 184, Folder 2)
      - Board of Guarantors, 1991-1999, (3 Folders) (Box 184, Folder 3-5)
      - Director's Advisory Committee, 1996 (Box 184, Folder 6)
    - Lionel Trilling Seminar Committee, 1966-1997, (2 Folders) (Box 184, Folder 7-8)
    - Paul Lazarsfeld Center for the Social Sciences
      - General, 1977-1996 (Box 185, Folder 1)
      - Announcement of Name Change, 1996-1997 (Box 185, Folder 2)
      - Lazarsfeld, Paul F.
        - General, 1944-1980, (4 Folders) (Box 185, Folder 3-6)
        - Archive at the University of Vienna, 1980-1984 (Box 185, Folder 7)
        - Correspondence with, 1941-1975, (4 Folders) (Box 185, Folder 8-11)
        - Festschrift--Qualitative and Quantitative Social Research: Papers in Honor of Paul Lazarsfeld
          - General, 1975-1979 (Box 186, Folder 1)
          - Background Material, 1974-1976 (Box 186, Folder 2)
          - Contributors